It’s the middle of winter, and the prospect of warm sunny days is a long way off.
时值隆冬，暖阳高照的日子还遥遥无期。
For some of us, it’s the most depressing time of year, where daylight is limited and the weather is often miserable – this is when the winter blues set in.
对有些人来说，这是一年中最令人沮丧的时节——白昼短暂，天气也常常阴冷难捱，冬日抑郁情绪也随之而来。
So what can be done to lift our spirits?
那么，我们该如何提振心情呢？
The shorter days and longer nights can make us feel down, and that can cause us to eat more and exercise less.
昼短夜长的环境会让人情绪低落，进而导致暴饮暴食、疏于运动。
Some fear loneliness and isolation during the long dark months.
还有些人会在漫长的黑暗月份里惧怕孤独与隔绝。
Those people who suffer this seasonal mood swing more seriously are described as having seasonal affective disorder – or SAD for short.
那些受这种季节性情绪波动影响更为严重的人，被认为患上了季节性情感障碍，简称SAD。
It’s a type of depression with a seasonal pattern caused by a lack of light and is thought to affect the part of the brain that rules sleep, appetite, mood and activity levels.
这是一种具有季节性特征的抑郁症，由光照不足引发，人们认为其会影响大脑中掌管睡眠、食欲、情绪和活动水平的区域。
Jenny Scott-Thompson is one person who was diagnosed with SAD.
珍妮·斯科特-汤普森就是一位被确诊为SAD的患者。
She told the BBC: “I struggled with periods of exhaustion and misery that seemed out of proportion to what was going on in my life.”
她在接受BBC采访时表示：“我曾长期被疲惫和痛苦困扰，这种状态在我的生活中多到有些过分了。”
She was prescribed light therapy, which involved sitting in front of a light box.
医生为她开具了光照疗法的处方，具体方式是坐在灯箱前接受光照。
As well as going outside during daylight hours, this is believed to help anyone who is affected by the winter gloom.
除了在白天外出活动外，这种疗法也被认为能帮助所有受冬日阴霾影响的人。
Although having more light is an obvious cure, antidepressants can help those with more severe depression by artificially elevating the amount of serotonin in the brain.
虽然增加光照是一种显而易见的缓解方法，但抗抑郁药物也能通过人为提升大脑中的血清素含量，帮助那些抑郁症状较严重的人。
But this isn’t suitable for everyone, and many of us can try to just alter our mindset.
不过这种方法并非适合所有人，我们很多人可以尝试调整自己的心态。
Clinical psychologist Laura Keyes says, “it can be helpful to think about how to adapt your eating and exercise patterns to the change of season, just as this happens in nature with plants and animals adapting.”
临床心理学家劳拉·凯斯说：“思考如何让饮食和运动模式适应季节变化是帮助的，就像自然界中的动植物都会顺应时节调整自身状态一样。”
It might sound easier said than done, but accepting winter and thinking positively may energise us.
这听起来可能说起来容易做起来难，但接纳冬天、保持积极心态，或许能为我们注入活力。
Writing for The BBC Social website, Esther De La Ford asks “What if we explored what this phase of winter has to offer us, instead of grieving those things that it is taking away?”
埃丝特·德拉福特在为BBC社交频道撰稿时提出疑问：“如果我们不去惋惜冬天带走的东西，而是去发掘这个季节能带给我们什么，会怎么样呢？”
She suggests we use this time for rest, reflection, slowing down, stillness and renewal.
她建议我们利用这段时间休息、反思、放慢节奏、享受宁静，完成自我更新。
Maybe this might stop us longing for summer?
或许这样一来，我们就不会那么渴望夏天了。